FREELANCER

Professional Profile

Accomplished PR and Marketing Manager with a proven track record and 10+ years of digital marketing (including content creation and marketing, e-mail marketing, PPC, SEO), public relations, event and tradeshow management, account management, sales, advertising and marketing management experience. Creative, persuasive, driven leader that is able to "think outside of the box" to come up with ideas and strategies. 7-3-7-3 on Kolbe Index (high score for business leadership capability and problem-solving). Tech, B2B, e-commerce and online gaming experience.

Qualifications

- Inbound + Content Marketing
- Copywriting
- SEO + PPC/SEM Marketing
- E-Mail Marketing, Social Media Marketing
- Illustrator & Photoshop (Design)
- WordPress CMS
- Journalist & Media Relations
- Public Relations

- Event Planning and Execution
- Event/Trade Show Marketing
- Internet and E-mail Marketing
- Vendor Relations
- Marketing Collateral
- Partnership Marketing
- Marketing Campaign Management
- Advertising & Marketing Strategy

Relevant Experience

Increased annual sales by $300\% \hat{A}$ through strategic marketing campaigns (for Payelp and Xsolla)

Experience

Freelancer Sep 2014 to Current

EPRIME GLOBAL, Coastal Environments, Pure Beauty Skincare & More il/4 City, STATE

- PR, Digital Marketing, Web and Graphic Design Freelancer
- Digital marketing (blogging, SEO, PPC), social media marketing and public relations management for EPrime Global, as well as brand identity, graphic design and web site design for Coastal Environments (a coastal oceanographic engineering firm in La Jolla) and Pure Beauty Skincare.
- Press clippings available, along with web design and content portfolio (http://h2digitalmarketing.com/case-studies)

Marketing & PR Director Nov 2012 to Aug 2014 Payelp it/4 City, STATE

- Created brand identity, designed and maintained web site, created marketing collateral such as the logo, event banners, newsletters and brochures for online gaming monetization company.
- Maintained the blog and handled all online marketing and SEO efforts, focusing on generating optimum ROI for this e-commerce company based out of St. Petersburg, Russia.
- Event management for company events including GDC (Game Developer's Conference), Casual Connect, Video Game Monetization Summit, Gamescom (Germany) and more-scouted events, created budgets, worked with vendors (design/printing, etc.), deliverables.
- Coordinated and managed trade shows/expos, which included working with the on-site expo team, the press (including press releases and follow-up stories with the media) and speakers at the event; I wrote the panel discussion questions, coordinated speakers and personally moderated many events.
- Portfolio available of design and press clippings; Social media marketing management: Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and more.
- Under my marketing and brand management leadership, the company grew within the U.S. market and acquired several (new) multi-million dollar accounts as well as VC buyout interest.

PR and Marketing Manager Jun 2011 to Jul 2012

Xsolla il/4 City, STATE

- Started as a PR Specialist and became the department head within 8 months for this Russian-based online gaming monetization company that was looking to grow within the United States.
- Collaborated with journalists and prepared and distributed press releases/news pitches.
- Event management for company events including GDC (Game Developer's Conference), E3, Gamescom (Germany) and more-scouted events, created budgets, worked with vendors (design/printing, etc.), deliverables.
- Coordinated and managed trade shows/expos, which included working with the on-site expo team, the press (including press releases and
 follow-up stories with the media) and speakers at the event; Managed design team for on-site signage and inserts, trade show booth design
 and also personally did various designs of banners, signs and handouts for events.
- Portfolio available of design and press clippings.
- Marketing management, which included digital marketing such as content creation and distribution, social media marketing, working with outside vendors and designers operating within brand guidelines.

Owner- Web/Graphic Designer & SEO Specialist Feb 2007 to Mar 2011 NORTHSTAR CREATIVE DESIGN i1/4 City, STATE

- Owned a small design and SEO company (freelance) designing brochures, corporate presentations, web sites (HTML) and SEO/online marketing including local and national search engine optimization for sites.
- · Portfolio available.

Jr. Media Negotiator/Buyer Jan 2006 to Jan 2007 EVANS, HARDY + YOUNG/EH + Y MEDIA Jr. Media Negotiator i½ City , STATE

• Negotiated rates and scheduled media buys for my clients (media buying & planning position) by researching demographics and Nielsen ratings (Reach & Frequency); familiar with SmartPlus software, Neilsen.

Education

Bachelor of Arts , Advertising 2002 MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY i'/4 City , State Additional Specialization Certificate in Public Relations Graduated With Honor Member of Phi Sigma Pi National Honor Fraternity Skills

- Strata/Stellar
- Nielsen Ratings
- Proofreader (AP Style) & Copywriter
- Software: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, After Effects
- WordPress CMS
- Public Relations (Press release writing, distribution, pitching and monitoring)